<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sort on Li. Mingzhi</title>
    <link>/tags/sort/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sort on Li. Mingzhi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 14:30:27 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/sort/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Algorithm: 1. Bubble Sort</title>
      <link>/p/algorithm-1.-bubble-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 14:30:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/p/algorithm-1.-bubble-sort/</guid>
      <description>Statement  This article is my study notes about algorithms. Please refer to the original work for more details and indicate the source for reprinting.  1. What is Bubble Sort? Bubble Sort is a sorting algorithm that is simple and obvious.
We do it in the following steps:
1. We iterate elements of an array in pairs and then switch them if the sequence of elements in a pair is not correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithm: 2. Insert Sort</title>
      <link>/p/algorithm-2.-insert-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 14:30:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/p/algorithm-2.-insert-sort/</guid>
      <description>Statement  This article is my study notes about algorithms. Please refer to the original work for more details and indicate the source for reprinting.  1. What is Insert Sort? Anyone who has played poker would understand what insert sort is.
Be cautious that elements to the left of the beginning index are already sorted, thus we can stop redundant comparison if the beginning indexed element is bigger than the previous one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GA: 4. Quicksort</title>
      <link>/p/ga-4.-quicksort/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 08:32:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/p/ga-4.-quicksort/</guid>
      <description>Statement  This article is my study notes from the book: grokking algorithm: an illustrated guide for programmers and other curious people. Please refer to the original work for more details and indicate the source for reprinting.   This chapter I learned divide-and-conquer and quicksort, both of which can help me solve problems elegently.
 1. Divide &amp;amp; Conquer  It can take us some time to understand D&amp;amp;C. Therefore, we will see some problems to learn about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GA: 2. Selection sort</title>
      <link>/p/ga-2.-selection-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 23:44:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/p/ga-2.-selection-sort/</guid>
      <description>Statement  This article is my study notes from the book: grokking algorithm: an illustrated guide for programmers and other curious people. Please refer to the original work for more details and indicate the source for reprinting.  Chapter 2: Selection Sort 1. Tips About Selection Sort  Your computer’s memory is like a giant set of drawers. When you want to store multiple elements, use an array or a list.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
