<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TOEFL on Li. Mingzhi</title>
    <link>http://limingzhi618.com/tags/toefl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TOEFL on Li. Mingzhi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 17:16:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://limingzhi618.com/tags/toefl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TOEFL W2: Job performance and mood</title>
      <link>http://limingzhi618.com/post/toefl/writings/job_performance_and_mood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 17:16:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://limingzhi618.com/post/toefl/writings/job_performance_and_mood/</guid>
      <description>Some people may think that they can do a better job and make fewer mistakes if they deal with things in a serious mood.
However, I believe that people should work out solutions with a light mood since it can bring them many benefits.
Taking things easy can help people relax and perform better.
According to a psychological report from China Daily, stress can have adverse effects on their jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOEFL W2: Money spent on arts or sports</title>
      <link>http://limingzhi618.com/post/toefl/writings/money_support_for_arts_or_sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 10:09:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://limingzhi618.com/post/toefl/writings/money_support_for_arts_or_sports/</guid>
      <description>A/D: Governments should spend more money supporting the arts than supporting athletics such as an Olympic team.  [Opening Sentence] Even though there are limited government resources for arts and sports funding, money is often misspent on athletics and Olympic teams.
[Thesis statement] However, I believe that governments should put more resources and money on art projects since it will bring a lot more benefits to society and people.
[Topic 1] Through their creation of the arts, some people become larger-than-life inspirations to everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOEFL W2: Rural areas or cities</title>
      <link>http://limingzhi618.com/post/toefl/writings/rural_areas_or_cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 17:37:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://limingzhi618.com/post/toefl/writings/rural_areas_or_cities/</guid>
      <description>DO you agree or disagree with the following statement?
People who live in small villages or farm areas are more satisfied with their lives than people who live in cities.
 Some people may think that people living in rural areas, such as villages and farms, are more contented with their lives since there is a better environment in Villages and farms.
In my opinion, however, most people are satisfied with living in cities because it can have more benefits than living in rural areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOEFL W2: New tech affect study</title>
      <link>http://limingzhi618.com/post/toefl/writings/new_tech_affect_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 17:33:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://limingzhi618.com/post/toefl/writings/new_tech_affect_study/</guid>
      <description>Some people may think that young children should not use new technology and limit their use of technology because it is harmful to young children.
In my opinion, however, new technology can be useful for children&amp;rsquo;s studies and bring them a lot more benefits.
Using technology can help young students improve their study.
Today, computers and the Internet are beneficial to students because there are many excellent computer tools related to study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOEFL W2: A/D: Teachers should assign students more tasks</title>
      <link>http://limingzhi618.com/post/toefl/writings/ad_teachers_should_assign_more_tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 19:09:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://limingzhi618.com/post/toefl/writings/ad_teachers_should_assign_more_tasks/</guid>
      <description>Many people may think that young students can learn a lot by doing a great deal of homework. However, teachers should assign their students with tasks that can be finished within thirty minutes since it will bring young students a lot more benefits.
Fewer assignments with crucial elements can help young students study more efficiently. People commonly held that the more assignments to do, the more young students could learn. Many students are frustrated with the burden tasks and thus tend to finish the tasks quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
